<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('challenges2')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('storm2')">Next</a>
</nav>
<h1>Before harvesting</h1>
<p>Select world <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;4</span> which occurred shortly after the garden
was seeded.  Some carrot seeds sprouted well, others yielded two or three plants while some
did not sprout at all.  Help Reeborg weed out the excess seedlings, and plant some new seeds
at locations where some were missing.  Here is a suggestion for some vocabulary to use:</p>
<pre class="jscode">
var carrot_here = token_here;
var plant_carrot_seed = put;
var remove_seedling = take;

function ensure_one_carrot_at_spot():
  ...
</pre>
<p>Do it!</p>

<h2>Ready to harvest</h2>
<p>The weeding went well (I hope!), the growing season is over and it is time to harvest.  Select world
    <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;1</span> or <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;2</span> and have Reeborg collect all the tokens which represent
plants to harvest.</p>
<p>Notice how one can view the world <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;1</span> as having horizontal
(or vertical) rows having the same length, while
world <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;2</span> can be seen as having diagonal rows having the same length.</p>
<p>One possible approach is to define a function <code>harvest_one_row</code> and a second one called
<code>harvest_two_rows</code> as well as <code>move_to_first_row</code>.  Using these, can write a general solution.  Note that these individual functions may have to be different
in different worlds.</p>
<p>With suitable function definitions, the programs for both world <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;1</span>
and <span class="world">Harvest&nbsp;2</span> can be written as</p>
<pre class="jscode">
move_to_first_row();
repeat(harvest_two_rows, 3);
</pre>
<p>
Note however that you may choose a different way to solve the problems than that which is described above.</p>

<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('challenges2')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('storm2')">Next</a>