<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('random')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('hilo_game')">Next</a>
</nav>

<h1>Communicating with the user</h1>

<p>When using Javascript in a browser window, one can communicate with the user
via some <em>modal</em> popup windows.  <em>Modal</em> windows are windows that take
over the normal program flow and have to be dealt with before anything else
can happen. There are three such modal popup windows:</p>
<ul><li><code>alert</code>: an alert box displays some text to the user;</li>
<li><code>confirm</code>: a confirm box gives two choices (OK and Cancel) to a user;</li>
<li><code>prompt</code>: a prompt box asks the user to provide some input.</li></ul>

<p>Here's an example of how to use them.  You should execute this program to see how it works.</p>

<pre class="jscode">var response;

response = confirm("You have to choose something.");

if (response === true) {
    alert("You clicked OK.");
} else {
    alert("You clicked Cancel.");
}

response = prompt("Enter something here");

alert("You entered: " + response);
</pre>
<p>Note that modern browsers will often give you the option, after a few such popup windows have
appeared, to stop more from showing up.</p>
<h2>Getting numbers from users</h2>
<p>We have seen previously that the character "2" is not the same as the number 2.
When we use <code>prompt</code>, Javascript assumes that we are requesting a <em>string</em> from
the user.  If we want a number, we have to convert the string into a proper number.  We can use
<code>parseInt</code> to convert a string into an integer, and <code>parseFloat</code> to convert
a string into a <em>decimal</em> or <em>floating point</em> number:</p>
<pre class="jscode">write( parseInt("12.3") );
write( parseFloat("12.3") );
write( parseInt("Hello") );
write( parseInt("12", 10) );  // specify that base 10 is used
write( parseInt("100", 2) );  // 4 = 100 in base 2</pre>
<ul><li>Note that NaN is a symbol meaning <em>Not a Number</em></li>
<li>By default, parseInt assume that we are converting a string into a number in base 10; Reeborg
will give you a warning if you do not specify the basis.</li></ul>
<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('random')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('hilo_game')">Next</a>




