<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('harvest2')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('center2')">Next</a>
</nav>
<h1>Stormy weather</h1>
<p>It was a beautifully sunny day. Reeborg was playing outside with his
friend. Suddenly, it started to rain and Reeborg remembered that the windows
in his house were all open. So Reeborg went back to his house and stopped in
front of the door, unsure of how to proceed.</p>
<p>Using the <code>build_wall()</code> instruction, help Reeborg close the windows of his house.
 When Reeborg finishes his task, he will
stand in the doorway, watching the rain fall, waiting for it to stop before
he can go back and play outside. The world is <span class="world">Storm&nbsp;1</span>.</p>
<h2>Reeborg's friend's turn.</h2>
<p>Erdna, Reeborg's friend, lives in a bigger house as shown on
<span class="world">Storm&nbsp;2</span>. Erdna was playing
outside with Reeborg when it started raining. Help Erdna close the windows in
her house.</p>
<p>Your challenge is to write a single program that will work for both
Reeborg and Erdna ... however, it might be a bit tricky.</p>
<p>Hint: to determine if there's a window at a given location, a robot may have
to take an extra step and, depending on the result, may have to turn around,
go back and close that window.</p>
<h2>After the storm</h2>
<p>The wind blew really hard last night.  There is litter everywhere outside Reeborg's house.  His parents asked him to go and clean up the path leading to the curb, <span class="world">Storm&nbsp;3</span>, as well
as the driveway: <span class="world">Storm&nbsp;4</span>.</p>
<p>Reeborg should collect all the litter, and put it in the garbage can, and
close the lid, using <code>build_wall()</code>.</p>
<h2>More yard work!</h2>
<p>
Reeborg's parents are so proud of his work, that they ask him to pick up all the garbage that got blown away in their backyard during the windstorm, as illustrated on <span class="world">Storm&nbsp;5</span>.  Have Reeborg pick up all the garbage and put it in the garbage can.
</p>
<p>Your real challenge is to write a single program that can help Reeborg do the cleanup for
all three locations.</p>

<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('harvest2')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('center2')">Next</a>