<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('summary1')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('center')">Next</a>
</nav>
<h1>Introduction to the challenges</h1>
<p>In the next few lessons, you will be presented some challenges.
What you have to do, is to write programs that accomplish what is being described as being Reeborg's task.
<b>You do not have to do all the challenges.</b>  The idea at this point is to get familiar with the way that
Reeborg moves and to identify patterns that reoccur when finding a given solution.</p>
<p>While you write your programs, each of which will consist of a specific of series of instructions,
you have the advantage of seeing the entire world all at once.  You should think of how Reeborg,
who only sees the grid square where he is located, could take advantage of clues to determine its
next action.</p>
<h2>Important information about saving your work</h2>
<p>In the editor panel, you will find a "Notes" tab; if you select it, you will
find a gadget that allows you to save notes ... including programs.  All your notes
are saved locally on your computer; thus, no one else can see them.  If you do save
your programs, you will have to note for which world they are designed.  To do
so you can use comments.  Alternatively, and this is perhaps a better option, you
can use the special command <code>select_world("world_name_here");</code> as the first
instruction.  For example, a solution to world <span class="world">Home&nbsp;1</span> would be</p>
<pre class="jscode">select_world("Home 1");
move();
move();</pre>
<p>Try it without selecting world <span class="world">Home&nbsp;1</span> first.  Then try running
it a second time with the right world selected.</p>
<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('summary1')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('center')">Next</a>