<p><small style="color:#900;">Discussions, questions, comments about Reeborg take place
    <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/reeborg">here</a>.
  <a href="https://code.google.com/p/reeborg/issues/list">Bug reports</a> are welcome!</small></p>

<a href="#basic-commands">Basic commands</a><br>
<a href="#about">About Reeborg</a><br>
<a href="#contribute">Contribute</a><br>

<h2 id="basic-commands">Basic commands</h2>
  <p> In addition to understanding Javascript, Reeborg, and all the other robots,
    know the following instructions:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><code>at_goal()</code></li>
    <li><code>at_goal_orientation()</code></li>
    <li><code>build_wall()</code></li>
    <li><code>done()</code></li>
    <li><code>front_is_clear()</code></li>
    <li><code>has_token()</code></li>
    <li><code>is_facing_north()</code></li>
    <li><code>move()</code></li>
    <li><code>put()</code> or <code>put("shape")</code> where shape is one of <code>"token"</code>,
      <code>"triangle"</code>, <code>"square"</code> or <code>"star"</code></li>
    <li><code>right_is_clear()</code></li>
    <li><code>repeat(f, n)</code></li>
    <li><code>shape_here()</code></li>
    <li><code>take()</code> or <code>take("shape")</code> where shape is one of <code>"token"</code>,
      <code>"triangle"</code>, <code>"square"</code> or <code>"star"</code></li>
    <li><code>token_here()</code></li>
    <li><code>turn_left()</code></li>
  </ul>
  <p>To create additional robots, one can use <code>new UsedRobot()</code></p>
  <p>In addition, the following commands are available and are not tied to
    any robot in particular.</p>
  <ul>
    <li><code>inspect(Javascript object)</code></li>
    <li><code>pause()</code>; can be called with an argument in milliseconds which indicates the
    time after which it will automatically resume.</li>
    <li><code>think(number)</code>: sets the amount of time in milliseconds between each robot action.</li>
    <li><code>write(string)</code>: write a string in Reeborg's Diary</li>
    <li><code>select_world(string)</code>: selects a given world.</li>
    <li><code>side_view()</code> and <code>top_view()</code> can be used to change the set of robot images
    that are used.</li>
  </ul>

 <p>To find out more, follow the lessons.</p>

 <h2 id="about">About Reeborg</h2>

<p>Inspired by Guido van Robot, itself inspired by the original Karel the Robot
created by Richard Pattis, Reeborg first appeared in RUR-PLE, a program I created
to learn Python, picking up programming as a hobby.</p>
<p>Reeborg is there to guide you in learning computer programming in Javascript.
Why Javascript?   The main reason is because it is the native language
for programming web browsers.  Since Reeborg's program is written in Javascript,
you will be able, after going through enough lessons, to change the way that
Reeborg behaves, using the full power of Javascript and perhaps make
Reeborg do things that I never thought could be possible.<p>
<p> I hope you enjoy learning computer programming with Reeborg.
<p>Feel free to contact me at
<a href="mailto:andre.roberge@gmail.com">Andre.Roberge@gmail.com</a></p>

<p>Reeborg is free and will remain free to use and to share under a Creative Commons License
<a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/">
<img alt="Contrat Creative Commons" style="border-width:0" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/88x31.png" height="31px" width="88px"/></a>
If you are using it to teach Javascript to students, you might want to make
    a copy of this site on a local server; contact me if you need help.</p>
<p>If you find this site so useful and you want to do something to thank me,
    you have two choices:</p>
    <ul><li>You can give me $100,000; small denominations preferred.</li>
    <li>You can <em>pay it forward</em> by doing something nice to someone else.</li></ul>
    <p>The choice is yours :-)</p>


 <h2 id="contribute">Contribute</h2>

 <p> I am just a self-taught programmer, with no training in web design, graphics, etc.
I would gladly welcome any suggestions or contributions to</p>
<ul><li>Improve the usability of this site.</li>
<li>Make a better looking robot; I drew Reeborg pixel-by-pixel using a rather primitive
    drawing program, suitable for my skills level. There are two sets of pictures available:
    one with Reeborg viewed from its side and one viewed from above.
    Note that the (imo) better looking Reeborg
    is viewed sideways whereas its world is (most often) viewed from above;
    a nicer-looking Reeborg, perhaps viewed
from nearly above, might be most welcome.</li>
<li>New worlds, examples and challenges.</li>
<li>Corrections to the existing content, including fixing typos.</li>
<li>etc.</li></ul>
<p><a href="https://code.google.com/p/reeborg/issues/list">Bug reports</a> are welcome!</p>
<p>My medium-term plans include:</p>
<ul><li>Translating the Javascript-based tutorial into French</li>
<li>Having a Python version (probably using <a href="http://brython.info/index.html">Brython</a>)</li>
<li>Having a CoffeeScript version</li>
<li>Tutorial on games using the html canvas</li></ul>
<p>Longer term plans include:</p>
<ul><li>Implementing Reeborg's world for other languages (Scheme, ...) as long as it can be
done within a browser with no server-side code running.</li>
<li>Enlisting contributors to translate tutorials into languages other than English or French</li>
<li>Investigating something like <a href="https://github.com/ryanb/ruby-warrior">Ruby-warrior in Javascript</a></li>
<li>Investigating the possibility of porting <a href="http://www.nand2tetris.org/">From nand to Tetris</a> to the web using Javascript</li></ul>
