<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('turn_around')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('reading')">Next</a>
</nav>
<h1>Using the Library</h1>
<p>When programmer make use of a given function in different programs,
rather than redefining it in each program they write, they put them in special
programs called <b>libraries</b> and they have a way to ensure that
their other programs can use the functions that are found in
the library.</p>
<p>You are going to use the function <code>turn_right()</code> <b>a lot!</b>
Instead of rewriting it each time (remember Rule # 3), what you are going to
do is to write it <b>once</b> (<small>more</small>) but, this time,
instead of writing it in the editor with the <b>Code</b> tab, you will
click on the <b>Library</b> tab and write it there.  Oh, and you should
also write <code>turn_around()</code> there as well.  Once you have done
this, you need to do two things.</p>
<ol><li>Click on <b>save</b> so that it will be available for you
anytime you come back to Reeborg's world. (I don't expect you to go
through all the lessons in one single visit.)</li>
<li>Go back to the Code editor (so you no longer see your <code>turn_right()</code>
and <code>turn_around()</code> functions)
and write a short program that nonetheless uses them to make sure that they
work as expected.  If they don't, go back and fix them ... <b>and save the version
that works properly</b> by clicking on <b>save</b> again.</li></ol>
<p>From now on, whenever you define a function that you use more than
once, add it to your library so that you don't have to redefine it
every time.</p>
<h2>Wait, there's more!</h2>
<p>We've mentioned it before but it bears repeating in case you did not read
it the first time.</p>
<p>In addition to the <b>Library</b> tab, you may have noticed the <b>Notes</b> tab.
If you click on that tab, you will not see an editor, like the other two, but a rectangular "box"
where you can put in any text you want and save it.  It's a great place to save individual programs.
There should be at least one hundred if not a thousand times more space provided by your browser
than what would be required to save all the solutions (programs), including comments (so that
you would know what program solves what problem) for all the suggested exercises and
challenges that you will find on this website.  Don't be shy, use it!</p>
<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('turn_around')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('reading')">Next</a>