<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('storm')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('summary2')">Next</a>
</nav>

<h1>Newspaper delivery</h1>
<p>Reeborg has a new job: he delivers the <em>Northern Star</em> newspaper.
Many of Reeborg's customers do not live on the ground floor of their building.
For each of these customers,
Reeborg has to do the following</p>
<ol><li>Pick up a single copy of the newspaper (it would be too heavy to
carry them all up the stairs).</li>
<li>Climb up the required number of floors to reach the customer's door.</li>
<li>Get the money (tokens) left by the customer.</li>
<li>Leave a copy of the newspaper (simply nicknamed the <em>star</em>) behind.</li>
<li>Climb down to the ground level</li>
</ol>

<p>While Reeborg has many clients, I only included two with their corresponding
worlds:</p>
<ul><li>The nice Ms. Ada Lovelace, who lives on the third floor of her building,
always leaves a couple of extra tokens as a gift to Reeborg; hers is
world <span class="world">Newspaper&nbsp;1</span>.</li>
<li>The old curmudgeon Mr. Charles Babbage, who lives on the fifth floor, always
pays the exact amount, leaving no tip for Reeborg; his world is
<span class="world">Newspaper&nbsp;2</span></li></ul>
<p>With the help of the following two instructions:</p>
<pre class="jscode">take("star")   // pick it up to carry
put("star")  // put it down</pre>
<p>make Reeborg complete at least one delivery.  Pay attention to the
two instructions written above and make sure, when you need to use them,
 to write them exactly the same way.</p>
<p>At this point , it may appear impossible to write a single program that
could handle both deliveries.
Later, you will find out how to do so.</p>
<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('storm')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('summary2')">Next</a>
