<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('center2')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('recursion2')">Next</a>
</nav>
<h1>Recursion</h1>
<p>If you look up on the Internet for a definition of recursion, you will often see something
like the following:</p>
<dl>
<dt><b>Recursion</b></dt>
<dd>See recursion.</dd>
</dl>
<p>This is wrong, wrong, <em>wrong</em>, <b>wrong</b> .... WRONG!</p>
<p>If you were a computer program, trying to parse the above definition, you would
get stuck in an infinite loop.  Since you are reading this, it means that either you
did not behave like a computer and got stuck in an infinite loop OR that you did not
read everything here and, in particular, skipped over the above definition.</p>
<p>Recursion is sometimes described as being difficult to grasp.  Do not believe this.
If you understand loops, you can understand recursion.</p>
<p>So, what is recursion you ask?...</p>
<p>Recursion is the process of repeating items in a self-similar way.  For computer programs,
it means repeating instructions - like in a loop.  And, like in a loop, we do not want to
get stuck forever.</p>
<p>The simplest example is that of a single recursive function, that is a function that calls
itself.</p>
<pre class="jscode">function recursive(){
...
if (!completed_task()){
    recursive();  // the same function is called ...
}</pre>
<p>Let's consider a real program for Reeborg to execute.  Select <span class="world">Home&nbsp;1</span>
and have Reeborg do the following:</p>
<pre class="jscode">function go_home(){
    move();
    if (!at_goal()) {
        go_home();
    }
}

// now do it!
go_home();</pre>
<p>Once you have tried the above and completely understood it, go to the next
lesson where we will consider a slightly trickier example.</p>
<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('center2')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('recursion2')">Next</a>