<nav>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('bugs')">Previous</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('toc')">Table of Contents</a>
<a class="fake_button blue-gradient" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('rule2')">Next</a>
</nav>
<h1>A token of appreciation</h1>

<p>Reeborg likes to collect tokens.  When he finds one on the ground, most often he
takes it; sometimes he puts one down as well.  The commands for having him do so
can be simply written as follows</p>
<pre class="jscode">take();
put();</pre>

<p>Select world <span class="world">Tokens&nbsp;1</span>.  There is a token right next to Reeborg. Note the number 1 inside it: the
number will change depending on the number of tokens at that location.
Next square, we see the outline of a token, with the number 1 outside it.  This
tells us that we should have Reeborg put one token at that location.  Once this is done, we can see that
it has been done correctly by comparing the number of tokens at that location (number inside the
gold coloured token) and the expected number.</p>
<p><b>Write a program to accomplish this task.</b>  Can your program
also work, without any changes for world <span class="world">Tokens&nbsp;2</span>?
The answer should be no, for now ... but, later, you will learn how to
write a single program that can work properly for both worlds.</p>
<h2>Try something else</h2>
<p>What happens if Reeborg attempts to put down a token when he does not carry one?
What happens if Reeborg attempts to take a token where there is none to be found?</p>
<h2>Being more specific</h2>
<p>When you ask Reeborg to <code>take()</code> or <code>put()</code> something, he
knows you are taking about tokens, his favourite objects.  However, there are
other objects that exist in Reeborg's world.  So, if you want to be more specific,
you can write instead:</p>
<pre class="jscode">take("token");
put('token');</pre>
<p>Note that the word <b>token</b> is surrounded by quotes, either single or
double quotes. Try it out!</p>

<a class="left-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('bugs')">Previous</a>
<a class="right-link" href="Javascript:void(0);" onClick="load_page('rule2')">Next</a>